Josh Woodcock // Full-Stack Software Engineer

832-247-8742 // josh@j0w0.com // github.com/j0w00 // www.j0w0.com // www.linkedin.com/in/jrwoodcock

Full-Stack Software Engineer with over five years of development experience building reliable, manageable, and scalable websites and web applications. By utilizing proper technologies and best practices for optimization and organization, I am motivated by improving analytics and watching the needle move.

Skills: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Node, Google Firebase, MongoDB, Express, Python, Django, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Cloud-based Deployment Services (AWS, Heroku, Netlify), Styled Components, Bootstrap, jQuery, PHP, Git, RESTful APIs (Google, Stripe, Twilio), Wordpress, WooCommerce, Photoshop, Illustrator.

Experience

Software Engineer

Music Audience Exchange (MAX) | January 2021–Present | Austin, Texas (Remote)

- Developed livestream web apps that provide fans with the ultimate digital music experience combining musical artists and top brands. Features include event registration, real-time chat, tips / donations via Stripe, and livestream video feed.
- Tech stack used includes React, Styled Components, Google Firebase.

Full-Stack Software Engineer

General Assembly | July 2020-October 2020 | Austin, Texas (Remote)

- Gained hands-on experience working with and utilizing several programming languages and web frameworks, while developing full-stack applications following industry standards and best practices.
- Tech stack used includes React, MongoDB, Express, Node, Python, Django, PostgreSQL, MySQL.

Front-End / UX Developer

Remedy | January 2019-July 2020 | Austin, Texas

- Streamlined web app for urgent care bookings that saw an increase of appointments by over 1000% and helped win
 two stages of VC funding for the start-up. By leveraging open-source web technologies, e-commerce, and custom form
 flows, the app was easily managed, scaled, and monitored.
- Developed admin utilities to help service coordinators better assist patients during the booking / scheduling process.
- Tech stack used includes React, Wordpress, PHP, MySQL, Twilio, WooCommerce.

MIS Web Developer

Ford Audio-Video | January 2017–January 2019 | Austin, Texas

- Designed and developed corporate website, allowing for easier management and sharing of content utilizing Wordpress.
- Developed and maintained web apps in PHP and MySQL for marketing events that included customer and exhibitor registration, check in and attendance, lead tracking, and online payments via Stripe.

Digital Media Marketing Coordinator

Ford Audio-Video | July 2014-January 2017 | Austin, Texas

• Oversaw the production of all email campaigns and web graphics, as well as maintained corporate website content, event landing pages, and company Intranet.

Education

Texas State University

Bachelor of Fine Arts, Communication Design | San Marcos, Texas | May 2014